Micah Evans

(He / Him) | mevans@miprev.com | 214.457.0824 | Greater Denver Area | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

PROFILE

Product leader with a track record of building high-performing product teams and leading organizational transformations to product-driven strategy and delivery. Change management leader who creates a shared vision and strong culture of respect and trust. Excel in mission-driven environments from startup to enterprise with domain experience in Fintech, e-Commerce, Marketplace, MarTech, Telecom, SaaS and more across B2B, B2B2C and B2C portfolios.

EXPERIENCE

Vice President of Product, Atlas Primary

2022 - 2023

Delivered product strategy for Atlas Primary, a mission-focused startup in the medical market research industry. Responsibilities included product leadership, building a technical delivery team, and transitioning development in-house.

- Hired six product and engineering team members and led strategy and execution for knowledge transfer from external software consultancy to newly formed internal technical team
- Created strategic roadmap and built product operations, requirements capture, and technical delivery processes

Chief Technology Officer, CREDO Mobile

2020 - 2021

Role expanded to oversee operations and additional executive responsibilities. Delivered against strategy for growth in core business and led innovation to expand into new markets. Core member of M&A team leading to company acquisition in 2021.

- Led product management, UX/UI, software engineering, data management, IT, and operations; scaled team to 55
 members with responsibility for \$12 million in budget and roadmap generating \$100 million in annual revenue
- Reversed declining trends in customer count and profitability in core mobile business, exceeding targets for customer acquisition while improving margin per customer by more than 20%
- Vision for new vertical expansion, including CREDO Energy renewable energy line launch to 19 markets
- Grew strategic relationships with channel partners including Apple and Verizon, and led mobile roadmap including launch of 5G support achieving 50% adoption rate 3 months post launch, and creation of BYOD program that within 3 months drove 40% of new customer acquisition at 30% higher margin

Vice President, Product and Software Engineering, CREDO Mobile

2017 - 2020

Product and technology leadership for CREDO Mobile, an SF Bay area mission-driven mobile phone company. Led digital and product transformation, built top-tier technical teams, developed roadmap and spearheaded technical innovation.

- Introduced and led company-wide product planning and roadmapping, balancing new product development with support and enhancements for existing products, creating alignment around strategic priorities to deliver growth
- Achieved a 100%+ increase in technical velocity, accelerating from 4 to 12+ major product releases annually
- Increased sales conversion by 20% through new features and personalization of content unlocked via revamped eCommerce experience on Adobe Commerce and launch of Customer Data Platform solution
- Enhanced reliability and reduced spend by replatforming custom software platform onto modern tech stacks;
 Migrated infrastructure to cloud in AWS, CRM to Zendesk, Genesys, and CallMiner NLP solution stack, integrated
 Twilio and Cordial for notifications, WordPress for content marketing, Authorize.net for payments, and more

Director of Product Management, ClickBank

2014 - 2017

Led product management at ClickBank, a leading global eCommerce retailer and affiliate marketplace providing end-to-end commerce solutions for product creators, marketers, and entrepreneurs.

- Managed product strategy for marketplace and eCommerce platform, crafting and delivering against an aggressive roadmap that enabled the company to reach \$500M in annual revenue
- Created and executed growth strategies that increased new creator acquisition by 15%, expanded marketplace and improved buyer conversion, achieving double-digit EBITDA growth
- Grew team of product managers and marketers into a high-performing division that exceeded goals every year

Technical Project Manager, CacheMatrix

2011 - 2014

Oversaw project delivery and client management for CacheMatrix, a premier Fintech SaaS firm providing solutions for cash management and liquidity to many of the world's largest financial institutions.

- Successfully led cross-functional teams of 20+ members to deliver custom trading platform solutions, responsible for delivering \$5M in revenue annually
- Product managed innovative fintech product offerings, including an integration platform that provided institutional investors with greater visibility into more than \$1T of money flows daily to money funds

Product Manager, IHS Markit

2010 - 2011

Led product development for sophisticated integrated financial data solutions for IHS Markit Digital, A fintech company that designs, develops and hosts custom websites, reports and tools for the financial industry.

- Led 20+ member cross-functional teams to create industry-leading financial research websites and apps for platforms including web, embedded (desktop) apps, iOS, Android, and Blackberry
- Managed and grew annual revenue by 30% from a portfolio of international banking clients through expansion and subscriptions to new high-margin financial products and services

Product Manager, Research Now SSI

2007 - 2010

First product manager for Research Now, the global leader in market research online sampling and data collection. Product delivery for internal platforms and tools, cross-functional team leadership and business process definition.

- Product managed quote-to-cash for integrated Salesforce, Savvion BPM, and PeopleSoft solution, unlocking the ability to deliver against an aggressive international expansion strategy
- Achieved 40% productivity improvement and \$1.2M in annual operational savings through launch of an innovative Adobe Flex based data query and reporting solution

KEY SKILLS

Product: Strategy, New Product Ideation and Validation, Product Market Fit, Roadmaps and Planning, Ruthless Prioritization **Executive:** Leadership, Digital Transformations, Pricing, P&L, Enterprise Planning, Sales Enablement, Partner Management **Technical:** Systems Architecture, Cloud Infrastructure, SDLC, Agile/Scrum/Kanban, SaaS/PaaS/laaS, APIs, Integrations

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

MBA, Strategic Management: University of Texas at Dallas

MA, International Management Studies: University of Texas at Dallas

BBA, Management: Pittsburg State University

Pragmatic Marketing Certification Level 5 (PMC-V): Pragmatic Marketing

Product Academy Fundamentals: McKinsey & Company

Certified ScrumMaster (CSM): ScrumAlliance

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner: Amazon Web Services

COMMUNITY AND INTERESTS

Mentor, ADPList.Org (2022 – Present): Provide six to eight mentoring sessions per month for early and mid-career stage mentees, covering topics including product management, technology, general career advice, and work culture

Volunteer and Foster, Western Border Collie Rescue (2015-Present): Perform fostering, home visits, evaluations, and general support to ensure that rescued dogs can be rehabilitated and placed into their forever homes

Economic Development Volunteer, US Peace Corps to Ukraine (2003-2005): Completed service as an economic development volunteer. Responsibilities included cultural assimilation and technical skills transfer

Activities: Backcountry and downhill skiing, skijoring, mountain biking, hiking, trail running, dog training, cooking, experiential travel, reading, social impact